Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you another part of our sports series and today we're going
今天我们带来体育系列的又一部分，今天我们要
to be talking about volleyball.
讨论排球。
That's right and we're going all the way to New Zealand to visit the Men's Volleyball
没错，我们要一路去新西兰，观看男子排球
Championships.
锦标赛。
So we're going to be looking at some great words and phrases related to volleyball and
所以我们将学习一些与排球相关的精彩词汇和短语，
also how to describe a sporting event.
以及如何描述体育赛事。
So before we start on the dialogue, let's take a look at two words on vocabulary preview.
所以在开始对话之前，我们先来看一下词汇预览中的两个词。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
All right, we're going to hear both of these words in the dialogue.
好的，我们将在对话中听到这两个词。
Now the first one, encounter.
第一个词，encounter。
Encounter.
Encounter。
An exciting encounter.
一场激动人心的encounter。
All right, so if we have an exciting encounter, it means we have an exciting meeting of two
好的，如果我们有一场激动人心的encounter，意思是我们有两个人、
people or two teams or two groups.
两支队伍或两个团体之间激动人心的会面。
If I say I had an incredible encounter last night with my best friend.
如果我说昨晚我和最好的朋友有一次不可思议的encounter。
You met up with your best friend and something happened.
你和最好的朋友见面了，然后发生了一些事。
Okay, so that's what an encounter would mean.
好的，这就是encounter的意思。
Yes.
是的。
Looking at our second word now, powerhouse.
现在看第二个词，powerhouse。
Two powerhouse teams.
两支powerhouse队伍。
All right, so we have two powerhouse teams, China and Brazil.
好的，我们有两支powerhouse队伍，中国和巴西。
That's right.
没错。
So a powerhouse team is basically a strong, powerful, really energetic, great team, right?
所以powerhouse队伍基本上是一支强大、有力、充满活力、出色的队伍，对吧？
Okay, so we can use it for teams such as in this case, but we can also describe maybe
好的，所以我们可以用它来形容队伍，比如这里的情况，但也可以用来描述
a company or a person as a powerhouse.
一家公司或一个人是powerhouse。
That guy is a powerhouse.
那家伙是个powerhouse。
He can lift 500 pounds.
他能举起500磅。
Now I think it's time for us to listen to our dialogue for the first time.
现在我想是时候第一次听我们的对话了。
We're going to be listening to this great sporting event as we are taken to New Zealand
我们将聆听这场精彩的体育赛事，被带到新西兰
to see China and Brazil play.
观看中国和巴西的比赛。
It's a beautiful day here in New Zealand at the men's volleyball world championship.
今天在新西兰的男子排球世界锦标赛上，天气很好。
My name is Rick Fields and I'm joined by the man with a plan, Bob Copeland.
我是Rick Fields，和我一起的是有计划的Bob Copeland。
Thank you, Rick.
谢谢你，Rick。
We've got a very exciting encounter ahead of us today as two powerhouse teams, Brazil
今天我们面前有一场非常激动人心的encounter，两支powerhouse队伍，巴西
and China, face off against each other and try to qualify for the next round.
和中国，将面对面交锋，试图晋级下一轮。
Without a doubt, both teams are in top shape and this will prove to be a competitive match.
毫无疑问，两支队伍都处于最佳状态，这将是一场竞争激烈的比赛。
The ref signals the start of the game and here we go.
裁判示意比赛开始，我们开始了。
Ribeiro serves and China quickly receives the ball.
Ribeiro发球，中国迅速接球。
Chun bumps it to the center and a very nice set by Chun.
Chun将球bump到中间，Chun一个非常漂亮的set。
Xu spikes it.
Xu spike了球。
Wow, what a great hit.
哇，多棒的一击。
The Brazilian blockers anticipated the play and tried to block him, but he managed to
巴西的拦网队员预判了这次进攻并试图拦网，但他成功
get the ball in.
将球打入。
Great play.
精彩的play。
It's China's service now.
现在轮到中国发球了。
What a superb jump serve by Li.
Li的跳发球真棒。
Oh, oh, and we have a let serve.
哦，哦，我们有一个let serve。
The ball was coming in fast and almost made it over the net.
球快速飞来，差点过网。
Brazil calls for a timeout and we'll be right back after a short commercial break.
巴西叫了暂停，我们稍后广告回来。
Well, sounds like a pretty exciting encounter between these two countries.
嗯，听起来这两个国家之间有一场相当激动人心的encounter。
Very good teams and both of them, as they mentioned, are powerhouse teams.
非常棒的队伍，而且正如他们所说，两支都是powerhouse队伍。
Well, why don't we take a look at some of the vocabulary that we came across in this
那么，我们来看看在对话中遇到的一些词汇吧。
dialogue.
We're going to be focusing on volleyball words here in Language Takeaway.
在语言要点部分，我们将重点学习排球词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, so in Language Takeaway today, we're going to have six words and let's start with
好的，在今天的语言要点中，我们将有六个词，让我们从
the first one.
第一个开始。
Chun bumps it to the center.
Chun将球bump到中间。
All right, to bump.
好的，to bump。
All right.
好的。
So, in volleyball, when you are going to receive the ball, you put your arms together and you
在排球中，当你准备接球时，你把手臂合拢，用
hit it with your forearms.
前臂击球。
That's right.
没错。
So at the top of your arm.
在手臂的上部。
Right.
对。
And that's how you pass it to another player.
这就是你如何将球传给另一个球员。
That's called a bump.
这叫做bump。
So it is a noun and a verb.
所以它既是名词也是动词。
A bump to bump.
A bump to bump。
Exactly.
没错。
Now, another type of way to move the ball in volleyball we heard in the dialogue is
现在，在排球中另一种移动球的方式，我们在对话中听到的是
a set.
set。
A very nice set by Chen.
Chen一个非常漂亮的set。
So a set or to set.
所以a set或to set。
Right, the word can be used as a verb and a noun.
对，这个词可以用作动词和名词。
And again, you take the ball and you move it with the tips of your fingers.
同样，你接住球，用指尖移动它。
That is actually done by the setter.
这实际上是由setter完成的。
Right.
对。
That is done by the setter.
这是由setter完成的。
And he does this, he sets the ball, so then the attacker can spike the ball.
他这样做，他set球，然后攻击手可以spike球。
That's our next word, to spike.
这是我们的下一个词，to spike。
So to spike the ball.
所以to spike the ball。
Or a spike.
或者a spike。
Is when you hit the ball very hard and very fast with the palm of your hand.
是指用手掌非常用力、快速地击球。
That's right.
没错。
And that's how you score your points, right?
这就是你得分的方式，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So you'll see three basic moves.
所以你会看到三个基本动作。
The bump, set, and spike.
Bump, set, and spike。
But what about the serve?
那发球呢？
All right.
好的。
So our fourth word in volleyball is service.
所以我们的第四个排球词是service。
So it's China's service now.
现在轮到中国service了。
Right.
对。
So the service is the opportunity for the team to serve the ball.
所以service是队伍发球的机会。
Yeah, pretty simple.
是的，很简单。
Right.
对。
And it's basically to start the game by hitting it to the other side.
基本上是通过击球到对方场地来开始比赛。
Now one type of serve is the jump serve.
现在一种发球方式是jump serve。
Jump serve.
Jump serve。
Now this is very popular and you will see some players do this.
这非常流行，你会看到一些球员这样做。
They will throw the ball in the air and then jump in the air and hit it.
他们会把球抛到空中，然后跳起来击球。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So that's a jump serve.
所以那是jump serve。
And our last word for today is let's serve.
今天最后一个词是let serve。
A let serve.
A let serve。
Okay.
好的。
We have a let's serve today.
我们今天有一个let serve。
So a let's serve is when you serve the ball and it sort of brushes over the net.
所以let serve是指你发球时，球轻轻擦过网。
Right.
对。
It'll hit the net but it will still pass to the other side.
它会碰到网，但仍然会落到对方场地。
That's right.
没错。
And that's an illegal move in volleyball, isn't it?
在排球中这是违规动作，不是吗？
When you are serving, yes.
发球时是的。
So a let serve.
所以是let serve。
Right.
对。
So those are the six terms related to volleyball that we're going to be looking at today.
所以这就是我们今天要学习的六个与排球相关的术语。
And well, with this in mind, let's move on to looking at some phrases now in, what is
好的，带着这些，我们继续看一些短语，在
it?
什么？
Let's go.
我们开始吧。
All right.
好的。
So our two announcers, Bob and Rick, said that we've got an exciting encounter ahead
我们的两位解说员Bob和Rick说，我们面前有一场激动人心的encounter。
of us.
对。
Right.
所以他们用了这个短语ahead of us。
So they use this phrase ahead of us.
Ahead of us。
Ahead of us.
基本上，这是什么意思？
So basically, what does that mean?
某事将在不久的将来发生。
Something will happen in the very near future.
所以他们期待它，或者可能会遇到它。
So they are expecting it or they will encounter it maybe.
是的。
Yes.
所以我们来举几个这个短语的例子。
So why don't we give a few examples of this phrase.
Marco，我们面前有漫长的一天。
Marco, we've got a long day ahead of us.
我们今天面前有一次非常激动人心的旅行。
We have a very exciting trip ahead of us today.
好的。
Okay.
所以ahead of us。
So ahead of us.
所以我们知道这是一场激动人心的比赛，我们听到解说员说，毫无疑问，两支
So we know it's an exciting game and we heard the announcers say, without a doubt, both
队伍都处于最佳状态。
teams are in top shape.
好的。
Okay.
所以短语without a doubt。
So the phrase without a doubt.
Without a doubt。
Without a doubt.
所以如果我用without a doubt开始一个短语。
So if I start a phrase using without a doubt.
你基本上是在说毫无疑问。
You're basically saying there's no question.
这太明显了。
It's so obvious.
这绝对是真实的。
This definitely is true.
非常真实。
It's very true.
好的。
Okay.
所以毫无疑问，EnglishPod是最好的播客。
So without a doubt, EnglishPod is the best podcast out there.
毫无疑问，这是我们应该采取的策略。
Without a doubt, this is the strategy we should take.
好的。
Okay.
非常好。
Very good.
所以without a doubt。
So without a doubt.
现在我们来看第三个短语。
Why don't we move on to our third phrase now.
这将是一场竞争激烈的比赛。
This will prove to be a competitive match.
所以让我们看看短语will prove to be。
So let's look at the phrase will prove to be.
某事will prove to be。
Something will prove to be.
好的。
Okay.
在我们深入之前，先听一些例子。
So before we get into it, why don't we listen to some examples.
例子一。
Example one.
我认为你会证明是我们有过的最伟大的总统。
I think you'll prove to be the greatest president we've ever had.
例子二。
Example two.
新的人力资源政策被证明是浪费时间。
The new HR policy is proving to be a waste of time.
例子三。
Example three.
我们担心会被解雇，但我们的恐惧被证明是不真实的。
We were worried that we were going to get laid off, but our fears proved to be untrue.
好的，所以当某事will prove to be时，它会显示出自己是这个东西，对吧？
Okay so when something will prove to be, it will show itself to be this thing, right?
它会展示出来。
It will demonstrate.
我们会看到。
We will see it.
我们会确切地看到它会怎样。
We will see for sure how it will be.
现在来看第四个短语，非常简单，但在体育评论员
And now for our fourth phrase, a very simple one, but very common in sports commentators
或你看比赛时很常见。
or when you're watching a game.
你会说great play。
You'll say great play.
Great play。
Great play.
我们知道play通常是动词，对吧？
Now we know play is usually a verb, right?
但这里它作为名词使用。
But here it's acting as a noun.
A play基本上是指体育或游戏中的一个动作。
A play is basically a move in a sport or a game.
所以当有人说a great play时，意味着所有一系列的动作、传球和
So when somebody says a great play, it means all the succession of moves and passes and
击球来得分。
hits to make the point.
所以那是一个great play。
So it was a great play.
你可以把它用于任何运动。
And that you can use that for any sport.
对。
Right.
所以我们现在第二次听对话，然后回来
So why don't we listen to our dialogue now for the second time and then we'll come back
讨论这项非常流行的运动，排球。
and talk about this very popular sport, volleyball.
今天在新西兰的男子排球世界锦标赛上，天气很好。
It's a beautiful day here in New Zealand at the Men's Volleyball World Championship.
我是Rick Fields，和我一起的是有计划的Bob Copeland。
My name is Rick Fields and I'm joined by the man with the plan, Bob Copeland.
谢谢你，Rick。
Thank you, Rick.
今天我们面前有一场非常激动人心的encounter，两支powerhouse队伍，巴西
We've got a very exciting encounter ahead of us today as two powerhouse teams, Brazil
和中国，将面对面交锋，试图晋级下一轮。
and China, face off against each other and try to qualify for the next round.
毫无疑问，两支队伍都处于最佳状态，这将是一场竞争激烈的比赛。
Without a doubt, both teams are in top shape and this will prove to be a competitive match.
裁判示意比赛开始，我们开始了。
The ref signals the start of the game and here we go.
Ribeiro发球，中国迅速接球。
Ribeiro serves and China quickly receives the ball.
Chun将球bump到中间，Chun一个非常漂亮的set。
Chun bumps it to the center and a very nice set by Chun.
Xu spike了球。
Xu spikes it.
哇，多棒的一击。
Wow, what a great hit.
巴西的拦网队员预判了这次进攻并试图拦网，但他成功
The Brazilian blockers anticipated the play and tried to block him, but he managed to
将球打入。
get the ball in.
把球投进去。
Great play.
精彩的表演。
It's China's service now.
现在是中国服务了。
What a superb jump serve by Li.
李的这一记跳发球真是太棒了。
Oh, oh, and we have a let serve.
哦，哦，发球擦网了。
The ball was coming in fast and almost made it over the net.
球飞过来很快，差点就过网了。
Brazil calls for a timeout and we'll be right back after a short commercial break.
巴西队请求暂停，广告之后我们马上回来。
So, are you a volleyball fan, Marco?
那么，你是排球爱好者吗，马可？
It's a very nice sport.
这是一项非常棒的运动。
It's very fast and it's very hard.
它非常快，也非常难。
But it's very interesting to get together with friends, maybe at the beach and play
但是和朋友聚在一起，比如在海滩上玩，真的很有意思。
some beach volleyball or something like that.
打打沙滩排球之类的。
Yeah, I think that's the best place to play volleyball.
对，我觉得那是打排球最好的地方。
You know, we even have beach volleyball up in freezing cold Canada.
你知道吗，我们甚至在冰天雪地的加拿大还有沙滩排球呢。
And do you have sand?
你有沙子吗？
Occasionally.
偶尔吧。
All right, so volleyball is a great sport, but now we want to know what sport you want
好的，排球是一项很棒的运动，但现在我们想知道你喜欢什么运动。
to learn about.
了解。
We've covered soccer, we've covered basketball, we've covered volleyball.
我们讲过了足球，讲过了篮球，也讲过了排球。
So tell us what other sports you would like to learn vocabulary and phrases on.
那么，告诉我们你还想学习哪些运动相关的词汇和短语。
That's right, you can tell us this and many more things at EnglishPod.com, our website.
没错，你可以在我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 上告诉我们这些，还有更多内容。
So check it out.
来看看这个。
Right, leave your questions and comments and we'll see you guys there.
好的，留下你们的问题和评论，我们到时候见。
Thanks for downloading and until next time, goodbye!
感谢您的下载，我们下次再见，拜拜！